Dimitri Kouvdis - Senior Front-end Developer

• Email: hello@dkouvdis.com Website: dkouvdis.com

Linkedin: uk.linkedin.com/in/dkouvdis

Github: github.com/dkouvdis

British and EU Passports Holder

Profile

I'm a Front-end developer with over fourteen years of development experience, including in the commercial/FinTech industry sector. I specialise in producing highquality interfaces for client-side web applications.

My job is not solely to write code. I aim to deliver an exceptionally functional end product, which adheres to high standards for all platforms.

Over the years of developing, I've moulded myself into a well-rounded individual who appreciates best practice and progressively keeps up with new web technologies.

Technical Experience

Strong experience in Javascript related tools and libraries

- Typescript, Node
- React, Next.js, React Native, Redux
- Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Pina
- Express, GraphQL, Webpack, Vite
- · Playwright, Cypress, Jest, testing-library
- SQL, NoSQL
- Datadog, Sentry
- Vercel, Netlify
- Firebase, Cloudflare Pages / Worker
- WAI-ARIA (Accessibility)

Ability to take on InfraOps responsibilities

- Infrastructure as code including Terraforms
- Setting up working environment with Docker
- Managing deployments with Github CI/CD
- Working with AWS and Google Cloud
- · Writing bash scripts for toolings
- Strong belief to enforce practice to use TDD/BDD
- Collaborating with Backend / Designers
- Mentoring junior / mid level developers
- Pair-programming

Professional History

Senior Front-end developer (Remote, Contract) | Air Up via Equal Experts | October 2023 - June 2024

- I played a role in building a new e-commerce store from scratch and launching it incrementally to specific countries while using existing Shopify checkout configurations.
- Hexagonal architecture
- Heavy TDD environment BDD (Playwright), Unit, Integration, Smoke and Synethic
- Run migrations in Expand/Contact pattern for Contentful
- Build components in Storybook
- · Port legacy third-party features from the old codebase to new project

Stack: React, Typescript, Next.js, Shopify, Contentful, Tailwind, Storybook, Playwright, Github CI/CD, Pair programming

Senior Front-end developer (Remote, Contract) | Parloa via Equal Experts | July 2023 - September 2023

- Three months contract, my role was to develop an evaluation dashboard for internal users.
- Implemented a user feedback system for Al-generated responses, interfacing directly with the LLM API for continuous model evaluation and improvement.

Stack: React, Typescript, Next.js, TRPC, React-Query, Terraforms, Google Cloud, Playwright, Styled Component, LangChain, Mongo DB, Github CI/CD, Pair programming

Senior Front-end developer (Remote, Contract) | Series Eight | May 2023 - June 2023

- Three-month contract as Lead Developer, spearheading critical support, extensive codebase refactoring, and implementation of a GraphQL API solution
- Optimized front-end performance and established robust coding standards, consistently meeting aggressive deadlines

Stack: Javascript (Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Pina GraphQL), Tailwind

Senior Full-stack developer (Remote, Contract) | Flink via Equal Experts | August 2021 - December 2022

- Several responsibilities spanning multiple teams, with a vast amount of tech stack (see last line)
- Support finishing up sprints, completing complex features, and mentoring junior/mid developers.
- Migrated some projects from Vue to React from scratch.
- Written Github workflows from scratch to be reused as templates to meet teams' requirements.
- Supported React Native team to maintain an app and manage deployments and releases via Github Actions and Expo.io

and many more

Stack: Javascript (Typescript, Node, React, React Native, Vue, Expo.io, Nest.js, Graphql, Auth0, Cypress, Playwright), Github CI/CD, Terraforms, Google Cloud

--

Senior Full-stack developer (Remote, Contract) | Pret A Manger via Equal Experts | December 2020 - July 2021

- Member of the Authentication team, specializing in Auth0 integration
- · Engineered and implemented robust user access control solutions for subscription-based accounts
- · Optimized authentication workflows, enhancing security protocols and user experience

Stack: Javascript (Node, Auth0, React, Next.js), TDD, BDD, Github Actions, Pair programming

--

Lead Full-stack developer (Remote, Contract) | Caterpillar via Equal Experts | September 2020 - December 2020

• Development of React and Node application to report on used equipment sales using data provided form machine learning.

Stack: Javascript (Node, React, TypeScript, Next.js), TDD, BDD, Docker, Azure

--

Lead Full-stack developer (Contract) | John Lewis via Equal Experts | January 2019 - August 2020

- · Working on micro-site for the upholstery department focusing on improving customers buying experience
- I introduced BDD (Cypress) into our daily workflow to improve application confidence
- · Frequently paired with back-end developer for system operability and structuring API
- · Provided mentoring to apprentice developers.

Stack: Agile, Pair programming, BDD, Javascript (Node, React, TypeScript, Next.js), Kubernetes, SASS, Cypress, Docker, Gitlab Cl

--

Senior Front-end developer (Contract) | 02 via Equal Experts | December 2018

• My role was updating outdated codebase and refactor React deprecated functions to support new libraries for handover.

Stack: JavaScript (Express, Node, React)

__

Senior Full-stack developer (Contract) | Klarna via Equal Experts | February 2018 - November 2018

Two in one role:

- Part of the Authentication team, maintaining the service, improving/protecting customers access, integrating several authentication methods such as SOFORT, Swedish Bank ID, Email Link & OTP etc.
- Worked on the login section of Klarna app in React Native, with multiple user journeys per authentication method. I was assigned to several tasks improving CI flow, such as publishing docker images to the registry.

Stack: Agile, Pair programming, TDD, JavaScript (Express, Node, React, React Native, redux-observable, Jest, Jasmine), Docker, Splunk, AWS, Jenkins, Bash

--

Lead Front-end developer (Contract) | HM Revenue & Customs via Equal Experts | January 2018

- · Worked closely with UX designers
- · Produced web prototypes to improve/test the accessibility experience for users with disabilities and learning difficulties

Stack: Agile, JavaScript (Express, Node), HTML, CSS

--

Lead Front-end developer (Contract) | Camelot Global via Equal Experts | Jan to Dec 2017

Two in one role

- I was a FE Lead to deliver two platforms Horse and Sports betting applications; collaborating with developers based in Athens (GR) and Sofia (BG).
- Three different projects, building several micro games featured page for LoRo.

Stack: Agile, JavaScript (React, Redux Saga), SASS, Freemarker

Mid Front-end developer (Contract) | Rightmove via Equal Experts | December 2016

• Executed a short-term contract focused on feature development and maintenance for a mortgage calculator web application.

Stack: JavaScript (Node), HTML, CSS

__

More past experiences

```
• Mid Front-end developer | VICE | November 2016 - December 2016
```

- Mid Front-end developer | Pulse Comms | November 2016
- Mid Front-end developer | The Frameworks Spark | September 2016 November 2016
- Mid Front-end developer | Club House | August 2016 September 2016
- Mid Front-end developer | The Frameworks | April 2016 July 2016
- Mid Front-end developer | Future Platforms | February 2016 March 2016

```
Mid Front-end developer | TSL Digital | July 2015 - January 2016
Mid Front-end developer | Bossa | May 2015 - July 2015
Mid Full-stack developer | Serieseight | Jan 2015 - May 2015
Mid Front-end developer | SapientNitro | May 2014 - October 2014
Mid Front-end developer | BT | November 2012 - October 2014
Junior Front-end developer (Johannesburg) | Flow Communications | 2010 - July 2012
```

Education

University of Johannesburg, South Africa

Bachelor of Technology Degree | Multimedia (2006 - 2009)

Hobbies

- Love good food, specialty coffee and travel.
- Enjoy being outdoors, espically climbing, snorkelling (spearfishing).
- Have an interest in macroeconomy, blockchain, football and rugby.